

Rebecca is a highly motivated and outcome-oriented research professional with a strong background in (Social) Virtual Reality development and evaluation. She has exceptional analytical skills, attention to detail, and the ability to work independently or as part of a team. Skilled in the application of various research methods, statistical analysis, and data visualization tools to develop meaningful findings and recommendations. As part of her research work on an interdisciplinary project, she has demonstrated skills in effectively communicating research indings and recommendations to stakeholders.

### research assistant & PhD student

born July 28, 1995 in Aschaffenburg, Germany

### Contact



rebecca.hein@icloud.com



+49 15756530824

ResearchGate



LinkedIn

## Education

Sep. 2005 - Jun. 2014 - Abitur

Rebecca graduated from the "Karl-Theodor von Dalberg Gymnasium" in Aschaffenburg.

#### Okt. 2014 - Aug. 2017 - Bachelor of Science

She received her Bachelor (B.Sc.) degree in Computer science specializing in communication and media in Computer science from the Hochschule Darmstadt (h\_da).

#### Okt. 2017 - Jul. 2020 - Master of Science

She then enrolled in the master's program Human-Computer Interaction at the Julius-Maximilians University of Würzburg. or her master thesis, she worked on a VR application to foster participants' pro-environmental behavior. The application was nominated for the DIVR Places award in the category "Best Impact".

#### Apr. 2021 - today - PhD

She is doing her PhD on the usage of social VR in foreign language education to support intercultural encounters. This work will contribute to the evaluation of how different immersive features of (social) VR affect inter- and transcultural competence and sensitivity. She has acquired the ability to design and conduct independent research projects, analyze data, and draw meaningful conclusions. Able to critically evaluate existing research, identify gaps in the literature, and develop new approaches to solving complex problems.

# **Professional Experience**

#### Jan. 2017 - Jul. 2017 - Internship

As part of her bachelor's degree, she completed an internship in the IT applications department in time:matters GmbH in Neu-Isenburg.

#### Nov . 2019 - today - Research Assistant

Since November 2019, she is a research assistant in the research groups Psychology of Intelligent Interactive Systems (PIIS) and Human-Computer Interaction (HCI).

- Balancing the demands of research, teaching, and other responsibilities requires good time management and organizational skills
- Collaborate with interdisciplinary teams to ensure project success and on-schedule delivery
- Present research findings and recommendations to stakeholders
- As part of the Event Support Team, she organizes, for example, the bi-annual EXPO (final presentation of the student projects)

### Skills

- Proficient in the use of design tools such as Figma and Affinity Designer
- Proficient in the use of statistical analysis tools such as R, JASP, and SPSS
- Excellent skills in MS Office
- Experience conducting primary and secondary research, including surveys, focus groups, and literature reviews
- Experience developing and designing social VR (learning) environments using Unity and C#
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills
- Strong problem solving and decision making skills
- Ability to manage multiple projects and meet deadlines in a fast-paced environment

### **Publications and Certificates**

#### **Publications**

All publications can be accessed on ResearchGate and the University website.

#### **Udemy courses**

- Figma UI UX Design Essentials
- Multiplayer Virtual Reality (VR) Development With Unity
- Blender 2.8 von A-Z

## Languages

German English Italian Swedish Native Advanced Intermediate Elementary

### **Hobbies**



Cycling and Spinning



Knitting



Yoga



Gardening

Rebecca Hein Friedenstraße 40 97072 Würzburg

GermanUPA e.V. Winter School

# **Application: Winter School 2023**

Dear Sir or Madam,

Würzburg, 12. Februar 2023

I am writing to express my strong interest in participating in the GermanUPA e.V. Winter School. I am a Ph.D. student and research assistant. I want to expand my knowledge and skills in User Interface (UI) and User Experience (UX) Design.

Although I have some basic UI and UX design knowledge, I have little practical experience. I want to improve my skills in this area. Therefore, I am particularly interested in attending the Winter School as it will provide me with a comprehensive understanding of the latest design trends and techniques.

I am particularly impressed with the extensive program offered by GermanUPA e.V., and I look forward to learning from experienced professionals and collaborating with like-minded peers. I believe that the Winter School will allow me to gain a deeper understanding of UI and UX design and network with other professionals in the field.

I am very excited to learn about the latest design trends and techniques, the principles of user-centered design, and the tools and methods. The various UI/UX aspects can also be adapted to developing and evaluating VR experiences. Therefore, the GermanUPA e.V. Winter School offers an excellent opportunity to expand my VR development and evaluation skills, too.

I am honored to participate in Winter School and look forward to bringing my enthusiasm and dedication to the program. I look forward to learning from experienced professionals, collaborating with other participants, and contributing to the program's overall success.

Thank you for considering my application. Hook forward to hearing from you soon.

Sincerely,

Rebecca Hein